[Music]
many and many releases we are working on
making connector more stable and
reliable and we achieved great progress
I would say uh but still with a new
release always new findings which are
coming via support channel in this
release we added four capabilities four
sounds long but in reality they're very
very small and if this video would be
focused only on those it will be very
short video. So instead I decided to
remind you all troubleshooting
capabilities we have in the business
central today and I will mention the new
uh additions as we go. Let's start
business central Shopify shop cart and
my first recommendation is to run sync
in foreground when you do
troubleshooting or when you actually
setting up connector for the first time.
Let me illustrate. I press uh some
button sync products and what I get I
get this notification that job queue
started. On one hand it's uh amazing
because I can actually continue and
press other buttons and do something
else. I'm not blocked. On other hand I
don't see actually if task is performed
and if it's performed and has a issue I
don't know. So it means I need to still
uh stay in the Shopify shop cart and
look at this notification and click in
this action and maybe refresh from time
to time then I can see error. So in
reality it's not actually uh allowing me
to do something in parallel if I want to
monitor the progress.
Another way to figure it out if job Q
had error is to navigate to roll center.
Scroll down to the shipify activities
and you can see the list of
synchronization errors. So it's a list
of failed job use but not all of them.
Uh the only ones which are uh filtered
by Shopify related job tasks. So it's
only specific tasks and object ids.
All right, something is failing. But if
I in the in the Shopify shop, then I can
disable this toggle. We change the name
and the tool tip to make it more clear
what is actually doing.
So now the synchronization will be
happening in the foreground. Let me
press uh sync products.
And obviously I have a very very basic
error. I haven't enabled connector for
illustration purpose of course but here
I see the very clear error message I can
copy additional information to explore
that's dramatically easier let's
activate
and now everything should work uh
smoothly so we solve the problem another
one which I also recommend as a second
step in troubleshooting is to explore
log mode so we have three options error
Error only, all and disabled. Disabled
probably not the best option ever. Error
only is good when you are configured
connector and it's up and running then
it will uh save some space on the disk
because it will produce dramatically
less number of uh lock entries. But if
you just exploring connector or
troubleshooting specific case, it makes
sense to activate all. Let's see what
will happen and what impact it has.
Let's uh navigate to list of the
customers
and try to add another customer
just to show you. I have a customer
which I created specially to demonstrate
export issues. All right.
All right. First of all, we do not see
the new customer expected because it's
expected to have some problems. But we
see this caller notification on top
which says that record was skipped for
some reason. Shopify connector runs
number of checks on customers and other
entities like products and uh shipments
and invoices and it can skip them
because it already knows that something
will wrong with uh during the actual
export. So it notifies you about the
error in a friendly manner. So it says
about customer and this customer has no
email address and email address is
something which we definitely want to
use when we exporting customer into
Shopify. All right. So it will be.com.
All right. We fixing customer card
and we are repeating the action.
So it was not skipped but still not
added. So something went wrong on a
different level. So in this case uh
Shify connector didn't detect problem
internally but probably Shify did it.
All right. We see that uh this
transaction actually uh had a three
entries. So connector first of all try
to
to find customer by email
then try to find customer by phone
number just to avoid a situation when it
creates duplicates on Shopify site and
the third one is actually try to create
customer itself and you can see that
this one uh failed it has a has error
toggle activated. Yeah, the reason you
can see the reason in the response there
is a field which is called a user error.
Phone is invalid. Yeah, definitely the
phone which I specified is doesn't match
any decent format and Shopify rejected.
So you can see that the good entries and
bad entries both are locked. Let's
actually delete all of them.
fix the customer
but also change logging mode to error
only.
Yeah. Let's go to the list of customers.
Add customer.
And for simplicity, my check will be in
removing the phone. Of course, you need
to correct the data.
And let's try again. Customer was added.
But if you go to the lock entries, we
see there nothing. This is expected
because no errors, nothing to log. So
this is like the two starting points
which you need to perform if you doing
troubleshooting. Activate running in
foreground and activate logging. Now
let's explore some practical cases.
The next scenario we going to explore
will be inventory level synchronization.
So, Business Central calculates it stock
levels and push them to Shopify. First
of all, if something doesn't work, what
to check? Documentation. Uh-huh. But uh
uh more particularly item product
synchronization. Make sure that
inventory track is activated on
products. Step number one, locations.
Make sure that you configured location
filters and selected stock calculations.
There are three options in the standard
connector of projected available balance
at date and free inventory not reserved.
If you have something else and it is
selected, you need to talk to your
business central partner because uh this
is one of the very often customized
areas when people change the different
ways how stock levels should be
calculated. So it means it might be the
customization issue. All right, we have
stock calculation everything here. We
run everything in foreground. Check. We
are activated logging. Check. Nothing
suspicious is there. What next do we
need to explore? We go to the list of
products and we scroll in the right to
the Shopify inventory fact box. And what
you can see that this asend desk has
stock on two locations. Yeah.
Main location and copy hanging. and it
was updated. You can see when and you
can see that what information was on
Shopify but that moment of time which uh
inventory level was on business central.
So now we expect uh in this uh aphend
desk to have 250 250 on each uh
location. What about Berlin guest chair
also 250 but only on one location? Okay,
we are up to something. Let's find this
uh product in Shopify.
This is our Berlin guest chair in
Shopify. And we scroll down and we can
see list of locations. And actually you
can see that only one location is listed
here. The others and in my case it will
be copy hacking. It's not selected. That
might happen if you activated some
settings which I will show you a bit
later in business central before uh
after you created created product in
Shopify. Which setting I'm talking
about? Location. When you export product
from business central it will
automatically create inventory level for
it and it will use default location. But
if you have more than one location and
you want to create inventory levels like
for each of those, you need to activate
these toggles. Then when you exporting
product to Shopify from Business
Central, it will automatically list
these locations as as once from where
this product can be on Shopify.
All right, let's go back to list of
products and choose a synchronize
inventory.
and scroll down. Now inventory fact box
for Berlin chair is different. So you
can see that Shopify stock is 242 and
zero ex exactly because this is the
stock level on Shopify product when we
added location there and after pushing
the information it's changed. Let's
explore.
You can see now copy Hagen also has 250
as well as main location. All right. If
that still doesn't work, remember about
logging. You can see the information
about last sync and last calculated on
that will help you to figure it out
which exact log entry in the log to take
a look. So then you can explore if log
entry contains information about this
specific product. So that will be like
the last one exploration. but least
present pleasant. All right, next
scenario. I'm in the list of products
and you can see that all but one
products are mapped. Yes, because this
is a new product. So, I need to create
it.
Uh I have now new action
which is called create item. Let me
select it and press create item.
And it's still not created. What's
wrong? Let's scroll to the right and you
can find that we have two new columns
has error and error message. Now you can
see the toggle. So auto create unknown
items is not actually activated.
So for some reasons uh
maybe template is wrong or maybe number
of series run out or maybe there is some
customization uh you cannot create
products automatically.
Then uh first of all you will see the
exact error in the list of uh products
and the second one you can actually
select these uh products and try to
recreate them manually.
Done. Yeah. So in this case product is
created. Now we have it. The next thing
which you want uh to explore here or
might want to explore here will be
related to pricing.
First of all,
explore Shopify variants. You can see
the prices. These prices are calculated
by Business Central and updated. Uh and
this is exactly information which will
be pushed to Shopify. But what you don't
see here
a field which is called compare at
price. So this is full price before
discount. So if there is some discounts
configured, you will see two prices
here. Price where discount is already
applied and this is the full one that
can give you some hints which will
explain like how Shopify connector
selected the prices. And the next step
will be to uh actually open the
product
and explore the all possible prices and
discounts. Uhhuh. I can see 300. Now we
have some idea where this information is
coming from. So like it is all customers
etc. Then I can check my settings and
figure it out like why exactly this
price was picked and not like something
else.
The next one will be about orders. You
don't see some specific order. You
expect it to be here. Why? Why it is
missing? First of all check it in
Shopify admin. This order looks
suspicious. You can see it's grayed out.
Why? because it's actually archived.
Archived orders will not be imported. So
if you want it, you need to make sure
that it is unarchived. You consider
changing settings in Shopify to make
sure that orders will not be archived
automatically.
Okay. Now back to Business Central.
Instead of synchronizing orders
directly, which will import all orders,
let's do it differently. Let's uh notice
the name of this uh section. It's called
Shopify orders to import. It's a
separate table with a list of all
orders.
If you press Shopify orders to import,
you will get the all orders. Okay, you
can see like the
the full list like including the one
which we unarchived. And now what you
can do actually if you want specific
order you can select the the store
and choose import selected order
was imported.
You can see that it's disappeared here.
If it if you would have some issues
about it, there is a field
which is called has error and if you
find the record with errors, you can see
the more details in the in the bottom.
But I haven't managed to reproduce any
situation. All right, order was
imported. That's good. Now you can think
uh where this information which we see
here is coming from and you can actually
inspect received information which was
received together with Shopify order. So
this is information which we received
from Shopify related to header. You can
actually do the same for lines.
This is lines Berlin guest chair.
It's a little bit more technical but it
gives you some idea if you're curious
about like which information is received
and which is not and it also applicable
to uh multiple other entries for example
transactions
additional information about
transaction. All right the next step
will be to uh create sales document
and order was created. Notice there is a
new fact box uh which actually shows
some key numbers from Shopify order
itself but also the same numbers from
the uh created sales document. It can be
sales order or sales invoice. So it can
give you some idea if you configured tax
calculation correctly. Let's open the
order and do one more uh one more thing.
We can actually archive the document.
archive order. Yes, we will archive it.
And now if we explore archived
archive sales documents uh with a page
inspector, you can see something. You
can see the Shopify related fields
Shopify order ID and more importantly or
very useful
in the lines Shopify order line ID that
will be very helpful in the exploration
of shipping scenarios.
But what if uh I don't need this uh
order at all. Yeah. So I can delete it
here. And the reason will be something
has changed on Shopify and I want to
reimpport order. For example, now I have
a different shipping charges. All right.
So
I deleted the document but it's still
marked as a as a processed. So I cannot
create new sales document after
synchronization.
So there are two buttons which can be
very helpful. First of all you can
unlink processor documents. So now I
mark this document as not linked. So
it's kind of free uh as as freshly
imported. But there is also another
useful function sync order from Shopify
which with help of which you can import
the updates from Shopify for this
specific order. So if you know that like
something has changed quantity or
shipping charges or something you can
always pull it uh uh individually and
now you can create sales document
and the new version is created. All
right the next one we can see that this
order was actually partially refunded.
Let's uh jump to to list of refunds and
press button create credit memo. And
this is a new feature which probably not
will not be seen by many customers but
only by consultant who is doing
configuration for the first time and
testing some scenario. So you can see
that uh something went wrong and the
refund account was missing. So I forgot
to configure it in the Shopify shop. So
right here I get all my details.
I can fix it and try it again. But let's
go to another scenario. Another scenario
will be related to orders and
fulfillments. Let's import another
order.
Let's pick for example this one
individually.
All right. I imported this order. So it
is uh
ready. I will create sales document
and I will post it as a shipped.
All right, it's shipped. Meanwhile,
somebody in Shopify
uh admin, they will also mark this order
as uh as fulfilled. Yeah,
by mistake. Something has happened. So
now when in business central I try to
synchronize shipment to Shopify let's
pick the the last one this one
I will get this notification that some
records were skipped during the
synchronization view skipped record
sales shipment header no corresponding
fulfillment lines found all right here
it's a moment to do some exploration
let's start with the order
here we have addition information about
fulfillment and fulfillment orders.
Fulfillment order it's like what is
pending what we want to import and you
can see it's marked as closed.
All right. So like indeed there is no
task for us to to complete. What about
fulfillment? It is empty but uh if we
choose actions
sync orders from Shopify
you can actually see that there is
already fulfillment. So it gives you
some some ideas like that something has
happened.
All right. What do we do? Uh next step
in this situation will be to go to
Shopify and cancel this fulfillment
because apparently it was by mistake. We
need to register it from Business
Central. All right. Unfulfilled. Now
back to Business Central. This is our
posted sales shipment which we know has
failed. Let me remind you a couple of
nuances. First of all,
explore Shopify order ID in the header.
It should have something. Also, explore
lines. So, we have a Shopify order line
number. It's not blank. So, it's a good
sign. So, this is correct. If it's
blank, then it means usually somebody
modified uh sales order after it was
created from Business Central and it
lost its connection to Shopify order. So
that will be a problematic in this case.
All good. So the only only problem is
that when we try to process this
document,
it was problem on Shopify site because
the order was already fulfilled. If you
press update document and you can scroll
to Shopify section, you can see there is
a Shopify fulfillment ID and it has like
minus one and it is editable. If it is
successfully synchronized, it would look
differently. But now it is minus one
means something went wrong. But we
already figured out what exactly went
wrong. So we will just delete it and
keep here as as a zero. Right? It means
we can try it again. Yeah, it's done a
little bit confusing on purpose so
people don't uh mess up too much and
check documentation first.
All right.
Another one. You can always uh review
the Shopify activities line where you
can see some uh some KPIs which points
to something goes wrong. So missing
mappings on customer companies and
products orders which are pending
processing means you haven't created
sales order sales invoice shipments
which are failed or uh pending and fail
shipments. Plus you can see the job Q
failures and the orders which were
processed but then update has happened
on Shopify site and this updated
information is in conflict which was
already happened. So it actually
requires extra attention from you. I'm
almost green. The only problem I have
shipment errors but uh I will figure it
out separately.
All right. Thank you for watching and I
hope this guide will help you to
troubleshoot if necessary. But my
biggest hope and what we spent a lot of
time making sure that it actually never
happens. Thank you. Bye.